Keator, Karli; Papers apap369
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Karli Keator Papers
1987-2006
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap369
.61 cubic ft.
Convicted of a 2000 murder in Texas and sentenced to death, Deon Tumblin committed suicide in his cell in 2004. This collection contains research materials about the Tumblin case, compiled by then graduate student Karli Keator.
Collection X
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted except for select files noted on the finding aid.
Acquisition Information
All items in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Karli Keator in 2017 February.
Historical Note
Deon Tumblin (1976-2004) was convicted of the February 2000 strangulation and beating death of a 75-year-old Texarkana woman. He was sentenced to death and was a prisoner on Texas' Death Row since 2001. In November 2004, Tumblin hanged himself in his cell with a sheet.
Beginning in 2005, then Sage Graduate School student Karli Keator embarked on a project entitled "Deon Tumblin: A Case Study." As part of this effort she traveled to Texas to conduct research and collected materials related to Tumblin's life and legal case.
Keator is now director of the National Center for Mental Health and Juvenile Justice and program area director at Policy Research Associates for children's behavioral health policy, trauma, and juvenile justice initiatives.
Scope and Contents
This collection is composed of copies of materials about the Deon Tumblin case that Sage Graduate School student Karli Keator collected and analyzed for a project entitled "Deon Tumblin: A Case Study." It includes clippings, legal materials, and a presentation by Karli Keator.
Please note that not all the pre-trial hearing materials are present.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged chronologically. There are no series.
Death Penalty; Capital Punishment--Texas; Keator, Karli; Tumblin, Deon, 1976-2004; Death Row--Texas; Tumblin, Deon, 1976-2004; Death row--Texas
- Psychological Evaluations of Deon Tumblin, 1987; 1992; 2001-2001; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
- Karli Keator Research, 1991; 2000-2001; 2003-2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Trial Evidence for Deon Tumblin Trial, 1993; 2000-2001; 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Volume 2 of 19: Pre-Trial Hearing, 2000 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Volume 3 of 19: Pre-Trial Hearing, 2000 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Volume 4 of 19: Pre-Trial Hearing, 2000 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Volume 5 of 19: Pre-Trial Hearing and Suppression Hearing, 2001 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Volume 15 of 19: Main Trial (1 of 2), 2001 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Volume 15 of 19: Main Trial (2 of 2), 2001 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Volume 16 of 19: Main Trial (1 of 2), 2001 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Volume 16 of 19: Main Trial (2 of 2), 2001 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Volume 17 of 19: Main Trial Hearing, 2001 February 14 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Volume 18 of 19: Main Trial Hearing, 2001 February 15 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Volume 1 of 1: Writ of Habeas Corpus Proceeding, 2004 March 4 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Evidence for Deon Tumblin Suicide, 2004 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Tumblin Offences in Prison and the Investigations Right Before his Suicide, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Attorney Gary Hart's Request for Major Use of Force Report and the Requested Report, M-05046-11-04, 2005 August 31 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Karli Keator Administrative Paperwork, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Broken Promise: A Case Study of Capital Punishment, 2006 (Dvd 1)
- Appeal No. H74097 on Direct Appeal Opinion, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Untitled, Undated (Floppy-disk 1)